<!-- development.xml -->
<developmentProjects>
    <project>
        <title> Web Interface: SQL and DB Management of online book store</title>
        <description>Created using PHP, HTML, and CSS, that's intended use is for 
        querying a database managed via MySQL Workbench. A connection is made for users to write and execute
        SQL queries from the db, and given results screen in table format. </description>
        <technologies>SQL, PHP, HTML/CSS, DB Management (MSQL Workbench), Github</technologies>
        <link>https://github.com/mvoggel/DB-Systems-SQL-Querying</link>
        <screenshot1> /images/SQLtest.gif </screenshot1>
        <screenshot2> images/db-home.png </screenshot2>
    </project>
    <project>
        <title>Python Data Analysis: Jupyter Notebook</title>
        <description>Data analysis programs using Jupyter Notebook, and numpy and pandas libraries in python.
                    Programs read data from an excel sheet (dynamic or static), and perform a number of actions 
                    such as PERT analyses, summary analytics, and/or Agile technique calculations. The actions are based on
                    user input.
                    Core concepts and code are being integrated into Snowflake, which connects directly with our PM Software
                    via an API connection. </description>
        <technologies>Python, Jupyter, Data Science, Google Colab, Snowflake</technologies>
        <link>https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1jyIJvvjXZZYEhVwKvrDeIZBttj-6AktA?usp=sharing</link>
        <screenshot1> images/manager.jpeg </screenshot1>
        <screenshot2>/images/manager.jpeg </screenshot2>
    </project>
    <project> 
        <title> Job Portal: JSP and Servlet Web Application </title>
        <description>Semester final project using Intellij and PyCharm IDE. JSP and Servlet web application serving as a job portal (similar to other
        job application hosting sites like LinkedIn), which can be used by both Job seekers, and employers. Uses JSP for
        front-end development, servlets for backend, XML as data storage/access/session data. MySQL Workbench
        utilized for user data, like username, password, jobs "applied", etc. DB connected to site, and fetches for validation. Users can control
        which jobs to apply for, and see the full listing.  </description> 
        <technologies> JSP (HTML, CSS, JS), XML, DB Management (MSQL Workbench), PyCharm, Intellij, Servlets </technologies> 
        <link> https://github.com/mvoggel/COMP6000-SemesterProject </link>
        <screenshot1> images/manager.jpeg </screenshot1>
        <screenshot2>/images/manager.jpeg </screenshot2>
    </project> 
        <project> 
        <title> Linux: Advanced OS Projects, beginner to advanced</title>
        <description>Advanced OS course projects. All projects completed within a Docker Image presenting the virtual machine being 
        used. Coded mainly in C, MakeFile and pthread understanding is showcased, as well as main and disk memories and batch processing. 
        Final project was fully functioning file system, which also simulates block management.</description> 
        <technologies> C, Linux, Terminal, Docker Desktop </technologies> 
        <link> https://github.com/mvoggel/Adv-Op-Sys/tree/main </link>
        <screenshot1> images/manager.jpeg </screenshot1>
        <screenshot2>/images/manager.jpeg </screenshot2>
    </project> 

</developmentProjects>
